Guide to the Connecticut Hall, Yale University, Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Connecticut Hall, Yale University, photographs
1753-2000
RU 700
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2
The materials contain photographs, slides, and pictures of Connecticut Hall at Yale, which was known as South Middle College from 1882 to 1905. Included are photographs of the renovation work completed in 1953.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by topic and subsequent accessions.
Scope and Contents
The materials contain photographs, slides, and pictures of Connecticut Hall at Yale, which was known as South Middle College from 1882 to 1905. Included are photographs of the renovation work completed in 1953.
College buildings; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings
- Photographs, Series I
  - General views
    - 1700s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1860s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1865 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1870s (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1880s (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1884-1886 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1885 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1890s (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1892 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - ca. 1894-1905, watercolor, artist unknown (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1901 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1901-1905 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1905-1914 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1906 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1914-1925 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - ca. 1915 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1916 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - ca. 1920s (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - after 1924 (Box 1, Folder 19 - 20)
    - 1930s (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1950s (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Renovation, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Interiors, 1874-1904 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Interiors following renovation, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Nathan Hale plaque, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Oversize (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Slides (Box CS1, Folder 3)
  - Transparencies
    - Exterior (Box CS7, Folder 123)
    - Exterior (cont'd) (Box CS7, Folder 124)
    - Nathan Hale statue (Box CS7, Folder 125)
    - Nathan Hale statue (cont'd) (Box CS7, Folder 126)
  - Folio
    - Louis Orr etching (Box DR21F69)
    - From northeast (Box DR21F69)
    - East view (Box DR21F69)
- Print of Connecticut Hall by John O. C. McCrillis, 2000; Accession 2001-A-095
  - Print of Connecticut Hall by John O. C. McCrillis, 2000 (Box 1)